Guide to the Humanities Council Records RG.9.5.1
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Projects, 1982-1996; 1 VHS; 82 audiocassettes; 747 kilobytes in 62 computer files; 15.25 Linear Feet in 29 manuscript boxes, 2 half-manuscript boxes, and 11 folders in oversize flat boxes
  - Subseries IV.A: Greenwich Village, 1982-1992; 3.5 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes and 2 folders in oversize flat boxes; 15 audiocassettes; 22.4 kilobytes in 4 computer files
    - Events, 1988-1992
      - Program Proposals, 1988-1992 (Box 65, Folder 3-4)
      - Washington Arch Centennial Reception, April 30, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Inaugural Event: "Writers Read the Village", 1989
        - Paper Records, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 5-7)
        - Audio Recording, October 10, 1989 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0238)
      - John Tebbel--"Publishing in the Village since 1900", October 24, 1989 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0276)
      - Arthur Fellig ("Weegee the Famous") Photography Exhibition at Grey Gallery, September 21-November 4, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Jesse Tarbox Beals Photography Exhibition, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Daniel Aaron--"Writers on the Left", December 5, 1989 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0270)
      - "Greenwich Village on Film" Film Series, 1989-1991 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - "Village Writers: The Bohemian Legacy" broadcast on WNYC, 1990-1992 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Thelma Foote--"Crossroads or Settlement? The Freedman's Community of Greenwich Village, 1800-1863", February 6, 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0267)
      - Lewis Erenberg--"Village Nights: Nightlife in the Village, 1910-1950", February 27, 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0274)
      - "Jazz in the Village" Performance and Talk by Richard Sudhalter, March 2, 1990
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0245)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0277)
      - Paul Baker--"Stanford White and the Village Bohemian Community", March 27, 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0271)
      - Professor Robert Sarlos--"The Provincetown Players on MacDougal Street: Theatre in the Avant-Garde Milieu", April 3, 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0275)
      - Professor William Taylor--"The Power of the Word: Greenwich Village Writers and the Golden Fleece, 1913-1929", October 18, 1990 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0104)
      - Ross Wetzsteon--"Maxwell Bodenheim and the Tradition of the Dissolute Poet in the Village", November 28, 1990 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0132)
      - Sally Banes--"Arts at the Judson Memorial Church: The Avant-Garde in 1963", February 7, 1991 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0131)
      - Peter Buckley--"Athenian or Bohemian? Astor Place in the Nineteenth Century", March 7, 1991 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0130)
      - Richard Schechner--"Dionysis in '69 in 1991"
        - Audio Recordings, March 19, 1991
          - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0127)
          - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0128)
        - Poster, 1991 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 16)
      - Event Fliers, 1989-1992 (Box 66, Folder 4, Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Greenwich Village: Culture and Counterculture, 1988-1993
      - Essay Drafts and Author Correspondence, 1988-1993
        - Mixed Correspondence, 1988-1993
          - Paper Records, 1988-1990 (Box 62, Folder 9, Box 63, Folder 1-2)
          - Electronic Records, 1989-1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_96
        - Daniel Walkowitz, 1989 (Box 61, Folder 13)
        - Thomas Bender, 1989-1991 (Box 61, Folder 9)
        - Paul Baker, 1989-1991 (Box 61, Folder 10)
        - Carol Ruth Berkin, 1989-1991 (Box 61, Folder 11)
        - Sarah Landau, 1989-1991 (Box 62, Folder 2)
        - Mindy Cantor, 1989-1991 (Box 62, Folder 3)
        - Brooks McNamera, 1989-1991 (Box 62, Folder 4)
        - Alfred Kazin, 1989-1991 (Box 62, Folder 5)
        - Thelma Foote, 1989-1991 (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - Joan H. Geismar, 1989-1991 (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - Bayard Still, 1989-1992 (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Denis Donoghue, 1991-1992 (Box 62, Folder 6)
        - Josephine Hendin, undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
      - Publisher Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 63, Folder 3-4)
      - Author Contracts, 1989-1993 (Box 63, Folder 5-6)
      - Book Drafts, 1989-1993 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Photo Captions, 1989-1993 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Book Press and Reviews, 1989-1993 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Book Launch Reception, 1989-1993 (Box 64, Folder 3-5)
      - Mailing List, 1989-1993 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment of the Humanities Grant Proposal, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Museum of the City of New York Exhibit "Within Bohemia's Borders", 1989-1990
      - Paper Records, 1989-1990 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Poster, 1989-1990 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Greenwich Village Program Publicity and Press, 1989-1991 (Box 66, Folder 5-6, Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Subseries IV.B: French Revolution Bicentennial, 1986-1990; 2.25 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes, 1 half-manuscript box, and 2 folders in oversize flat boxes; 28 audiocassettes; 29.9 kilobytes in 7 computer files
    The Humanities Council began planning programming related to the 1989 bicentennial of the French Revolution in 1986, and facilitated related events in 1988 and 1989. Many educational and cultural institutions marked the Bicentennial with events, programs, and publications, and NYU was part of a New York City area consortium of institutions recognizing the milestone. The French government supported these efforts globally, and French President François Mitterand visited NYU in 1988 and gave a convocation speech. A National Endowment for the Humanities grant partially funded the French Revolution project at NYU. The Florence J. Gould Foundation funded "The French Revolution and its Modern Legacy" lecture series. Some of these lectures were also broadcast on WNYU.
    Subseries IV.C French Revolution Bicentennial (dated 1986-1990) contains files from the New York City area planning committee, the NYU planning committee, and the proposal, interim, final, and expense reports related to the National Endowment for the Humanities grant. The overall program is documented with calendars for NYU and NYC area events, press clippings, publicity materials including posters and brochures, budgets, and event photographs. Grant reports and project budgets are documented with born-digital and paper records. The Council produced a French Revolution study guide, and this subseries includes background research files, drafts, and copies of the guide. The Florence J. Gould Lecture Series is documented with audio recordings of the lectures.
    - New York Area Institutions Planning Committee, 1986-1989 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - The French Revolution and its Modern Legacy Distinguished Lecture Series (Florence J. Gould Foundation sponsored Lecture Series), 1987-1988 (Box 59, Folder 7-8)
      - Mona Ozouf--"Festivals and Revolution", October 6, 1988 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0255)
      - Robert Rosenblum--"Art in Jefferson's Paris", November 3, 1988 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0237)
      - Michel Vovelle--"Imagery: A Mirror on the French Revolution", November 7, 1988 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0257)
      - Régis Bebray--"Le Révolution et le Sacré: Why the Republican Revolution Could Not Do Without the Idea of God", November 17, 1988 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0256)
      - Daniel Roche--"Culture in Paris on the Eve of the Revolution", December 8, 1988
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0074)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0254)
      - Kieth M. Baker--"The Creation of Revolutionary Ideology", March 7, 1989 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0241)
      - Darlene Levy Lecture, March 30, 1989 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0249)
      - Élisabeth Badinter and Robert Badinter--"Concordet: An Intellectual in Politics", April 4, 1989
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0246)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0248)
      - Ronald Paulson and Paul Sheats--"The French Revolution in English Literature: The Reaction and Rise of Napoleon", April 26, 1989 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0244)
      - E.P. Thompson and Peter Thorslev--"The French Revolution in English Literature: The Liberal Persistence, 1815 and After", May 4, 1989 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0260)
      - Franklin Knight--"Impact of the French Revolution on the Caribbean 1789-1810" on WNYC, June 4, 1989
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0242)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0243)
      - Darline Levy--"Rights of Man, Claims of Women; Gender, Citizenship, and Revolutionary Paris" on WNYC, June 11, 1989 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0235)
      - Elie Wiesel--"The Philosophic Implications of the Declaration of the Rights of Man in the 20th Century", December 6, 1989 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0240)
      - Robert Darnton--"From Enlightenment to Revolution" on WNYC, June 25, 1989
        - Audio -- 1 of 3 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0234)
        - Audio -- 2 of 3 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0264)
        - Audio -- 3 of 3 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0273)
      - Robert Forster--"The Rights of Man and Citizen, Slavery, and Revolutionary Claims", 1989
        - Posters, 1989 (Box 74, Folder 9)
        - Audio Recordings, January 30, 1989
          - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0239)
          - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0253)
      - Marilyn Butler and David Bromwich--"The French Revolution in English Literature: The Political Background", March 28, 1989 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0247)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Grant, 1987-1990 (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Proposal, 1987 (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Interim Reports, 1987-1989
        - Paper Records, 1987-1989 (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
        - Electronic Records, 1989; RG_9-5-1_ER_95
      - Expense Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
      - Final Reports, 1990 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - François Mitterand Speech, 1988
      - Audio Recordings, September 28, 1988
        - Audio -- 1 of 6 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0283)
        - Audio -- 2 of 6 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0284)
        - Audio -- 3 of 6 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0285)
        - Audio -- 4 of 6 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0286)
        - Audio -- 5 of 6 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0287)
        - Audio -- 6 of 6 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0288)
      - Paper Records, 1988 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Mailing Lists, 1988 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Calendar of Events, 1988-1989 (Box 59, Folder 11, Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Publicity, 1988-1989 (Box 60, Folder 7, Box 88, Folder 15, Box 74)
    - Press, 1988-1989 (Box 74, Folder 2, Box 88, Folder 15)
    - Program Overview, 1988-1989 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Posters, 1988-1989 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 4)
    - Background Research and Study Guide, 1988-1989 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
    - List of Events, 1988-1989 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Budget and Expenses, 1988-1990
      - Paper Records, 1988-1990 (Box 61, Folder 5-6)
      - Electronic Records, 1988-1990; RG_9-5-1_ER_94
    - NYU Planning Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Event Photographs, undated (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV.C: Christopher Columbus Quincentennial, 1988-1993; 8.5 Linear Feet in 16 manuscript boxes and 7 folders in oversize flat boxes; 1 VHS; 37 audiocassettes; 363.2 kilobytes in 22 computer files
    In 1992, many cultural and educational institutions marked the quincentennial anniversary of Christopher Columbus's arrival in North America, and the Humanities Council began planning its programs in 1988. The Council participated in New York City metro area planning groups, including the Columbus Consortium and the Columbus Quincentenary Jubilee Commission. The Council planned programming under the broader title "Crosscurrents of Culture." These events included lectures, symposia, and art exhibitions during the 1991-1992 academic year. They focused on topics related to European history during Columbus's lifetime and the effects of the arrival of Europeans in the Americas, including the expulsion of Jewish peoples from Spain, Indigenous peoples in the Americas, the development of science in the 15th century, and human enslavement. A National Endowment for the Humanities grant partially funded this project, and the Instituto Nazionale per il Commercia Estero [Italian Trade Commission] funded a lecture series titled "The Age of Discoveries and Italy's Economy."
    Subseries IV.C Christopher Columbus Quincentennial (dated 1988-1993) contains records documenting project planning, including research files, records of planning committees both inside and outside of NYU, budgets, correspondence, and program and speaker proposals. The subseries also includes files on outside institutions that commemorated the quincentenary and quincentenary events in the greater New York City area. Marketing and publicity materials and press clippings document how the Council's project and the Columbus Quincentenary were discussed, promoted, and received. It also includes a study guide produced by the Council, event programs, materials related to the National Endowment for the Humanities grant, and other funding sources. "Crosscurrents of Culture" events are documented by correspondence with participants, invitations, summaries or transcripts, posters, flyers, brochures, and lists of invitees. Some events are also documented by audio recordings, and one, the Voices of the Encounter Symposium, is documented with a video recording as well.
    - New York City Board of Education Multicultural Education Grant, 1988 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Columbus Consortium, 1989 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Columbus Quincentenary Jubilee Commission, 1989-1991 (Box 77, Folder 6-7)
    - Other Institutions, 1989-1994
      - California Columbus Quincentenary Commission, 1989-1991 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Operation Sail, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - National Museum of the American Indian, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - State of New York Italian-American Legislators' Club Columbus Jubilee Committee, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - University College Galway, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Adventures in Spain, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - New York Public Library, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Italian Trade Commission (Instituto nazionale per il Commercia Estero I.C.E.), 1991
        - Paper Records, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 3)
        - Electronic Records, 1991; RG_9-5-1_ER_98
      - New-York Historical Society, 1991-1992 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Spain '92, 1991-1993 (Box 79, Folder 1-3)
      - New York State Christopher Columbus Quincentennary Commission, 1991-1993 (Box 78, Folder 11-12)
      - Center for Migration Studies, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Native American Council of NYC, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Voice of the Turtle, 1992 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - Columbus Countdown, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Puerto Rico, 1994 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Quincentenary Committee, 1989-1992 (Box 79, Folder 10-11, Box 80, Folder 1-5)
    - 1492: Crosscurrents of Culture Summary Planning Paper, 1989-1990 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - National Endowment of the Humanities Proposal, Reports, Correspondence, 1990-1993
      - Potential Participants, 1990-1991 (Box 70, Folder 1-6, Box 71, Folder 1-5)
      - Planning Files, 1990-1992 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 69, Folder 2-5)
      - Proposal, March 1990 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Interim Reports, 1990-1992
        - Paper Records, 1990-1992 (Box 69, Folder 7, Box 72, Folder 1-2)
        - Electronic Records, 1990-1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_100
      - Final Report, April 1993 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Expense Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Marketing and Solicitations, 1990-1993 (Box 73, Folder 8-10, Box 75, Folder 1)
    - King Juan Carlos Distinguished Lecture Series, 1990 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Research Files, 1990-1991 (Box 72, Folder 6-8)
    - Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 80, Folder 7-8)
    - Press Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 6, Box 75, Folder 9, Box 77, Folder 1-4)
    - Event Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 80, Folder 9-10)
    - Proposed Programs and Speakers, 1990-1992 (Box 81)
    - Non-NYU Events, 1990-1992
      - Clippings, 1990-1992 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 7, Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 6)
      - Calendar, 1990-1992 (Box 78, Folder 1-2, Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 6)
    - Non-NEH Funding, 1990-1992 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 81, Folder 7-9, Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Publications Planning, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Study Guide, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 9, Box 73, Folder 1-7, Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Publicity, 1991-1992
      - Television and Radio, 1990-1991 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Outside Publications and Publicity, 1991-1992 (Box 75, Folder 7-8)
      - Flyers and Posters, 1991-1992 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 1, Box 88, Folder 3, Box 74)
    - Calendars, 1991-1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_93
    - Mailing Lists, 1991-1992
      - Paper Records, 1991-1992 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Electronic Records, 1991-1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_92
    - Talking Points for Deans' Meeting, September 1991 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - "In Their Own Voices" Readings, 1991 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Voices of the Encounter Symposium, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 3-8)
      - Audio Recordings, October 7-8, 1991
        - Audio -- 1 of 4 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0265)
        - Audio -- 2 of 4 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0266)
        - Audio -- 3 of 4 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0012)
        - Audio -- 4 of 4 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0024)
      - Video Recording, October 7, 1991 (Box 76, Vhs 9-5-1.0001)
    - Crosscurrents of Culture Posters, 1991 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 3)
    - The Italian Renaissance and the World of 1492 Symposium, 1991
      - Paper Records, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 9)
      - Audio Recordings, November 6, 1991
        - Audio -- 1 of 6 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0118)
        - Audio -- 2 of 6 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0119)
        - Audio -- 3 of 6 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0108)
        - Audio -- 4 of 6 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0008)
        - Audio -- 5 of 6 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0018)
        - Audio -- 6 of 6 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0027)
    - The World on the Eve of 1492 Opening Program, 1991
      - Paper Records, 1991 (Box 83, Folder 1-2)
      - Audio Recordings, October 8, 1991
        - Audio -- 1 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0120)
        - Audio -- 2 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0121)
        - Audio -- 3 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0122)
        - Audio -- 4 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0123)
    - Europe Imagines America, 1991
      - Paper Records, 1991 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Audio Recordings, December 12, 1991
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0116)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0117)
    - Columbus Quincentennial Art Exhibitions, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Inter/Multi Cultural Events Poster, 1991-1992 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Enslavement Symposium, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 83, Folder 4-5)
      - Poster, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Islamic Spain, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Lecture: Robert I. Burns--"The Changing Face of Muslim Spain: Mudejar Foundations of the Morisco Tragedy", 1992
        - Audio Recordings, March 4, 1992
          - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0114)
          - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0115)
        - Electronic Records, 1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_83
    - The Expulsion of Jews from Spain 1492: Preconditions and Impact, March 29-30, 1992
      - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0019)
      - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0033)
    - Representing Native Americans Symposium and Film Series, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Poster, 1992 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Five Centuries: Many Peoples, Many Pasts Symposia, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Electronic Records, 1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_90
      - Audio Recordings, July 6, 1992
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0014)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0015)
    - Rewriting 1492: Images of Conquest, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Historical and Economic Topics Related to Italy Lecture Series, September 1992 (Box 84, Folder 4-5, Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Inventing Identities in the New World Lecture, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Audio Recording, October 29, 1992 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0011)
    - Palladio Exhibit at the Grey Art Gallery "Due Case, Una Tradizione", 1992 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - The Encounter with the Other Symposium, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 9, Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Audio Recordings, October 11, 1992
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0006)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0165)
    - Voyages and Encounters: Science Fiction as a Metaphor for Colonial Discovery, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Andean Worlds: The Incas, Colonial Cultures, Contemporary Legacies, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 11)
      - Audio Recordings, March 7, 1992
        - Audio -- 1 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0109)
        - Audio -- 2 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0110)
        - Audio -- 3 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0111)
        - Audio -- 4 of 4 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0112)
    - Legacies of 1492 Symposium, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 2-3)
      - Audio Recordings, December 2, 1992
        - Audio -- 1 of 4 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0016)
        - Audio -- 2 of 4 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0031)
        - Audio -- 3 of 4 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0177)
        - Audio -- 4 of 4 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0184)
    - Biotic Exchange Symposium, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 4-5)
      - Audio Recordings, November 17, 1992
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0163)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0185)
    - The Age of Discoveries and Italy's Economy Lectures, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 5, Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Audio Recording, October 5, 1992 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0010)
    - Gerald Holton "The Discovery of Trust in Science", 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Poster, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Audio Recording, April 13, 1992 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0030)
  - Subseries IV.D: Other Projects, 1986-1996; 4.25 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes, 1 half-manuscript box, and 2 folders in oversize flat boxes; 331.3 kilobytes in 29 computer files; 2 audiocassettes